Topical and hateful.
Unfiltered and independent.
100% authentic and intelligent.
All right. Are y'all ready? Bust out
your Amanda Landers notebook, get your
word of the day logbook, and let's get
into it. Don't forget, after the show,
our Seal Squad members head on over to
Patreon for the after show kickback,
[music] where we talk about all the
things that went on in the show and how
to turn it into action.
You ready? Amanda Landers!
Learners!
>> [singing]
[music]
[singing]
>> Hello. [screaming]
>> [cheering]
>> Hello.
I don't even know how I'm here right
now. I got food in my teeth.
Listen.
Your girl is going to Cuba tomorrow.
And I've I've got things to do.
So,
this this episode
is going to feature
um Aiden Simmerdon, who is going to be
joining us to talk about
all things It On.
And then, we going to head over to the
Seal Squad kickback.
And you I I'm I I
>> [laughter]
>> I I HAVE TO FINISH GETTING ORGANIZED.
I have to finish getting organized. I I
need y'all to understand.
I have to finish Listen, Jonathan. I
went and got the bug spray with the
DEET, like the higher level, you know? I
mean, I I'm telling you. My sweater
Can we just acknowledge
MY SLEEVE?
WHAT?
IT'S CENTRAL PARK.
THE SWEATER
IS CENTRAL PARK.
HONEY.
SO,
um
yes, I'll have the bug spray. I'll have
the sunscreen. It was so funny because
in the
um
>> [laughter]
>> in like the the
breakdown of like what we need to be
prepare, it literally said,
"It's going to be hot.
People have gotten sunburned.
Don't let it be you."
I said, "I I I hear you loud
and clear.
Okay? Loud and clear
is what I do.
Um
Apparently, Europeans are discouraged to
travel to Cuba and can't use free visa
privilege when entering the United
States.
It's It's a lot going on. Um it's
fascinating when people I've had people
tell me I'm being a tourist.
Um
Okay, Jonathan, let's not get out of
hand. Jonathan said a good wide brim
hat. Jonathan, I'm a island girl.
Never forget it. I'm an island girl.
I did forget to bring Dramamine, but I
don't plan to be on a boat.
Um
>> [sighs]
>> Okay.
I have been
AP adulting all day.
I've I've had
I You know, AP adulting is when you do
the errands. Y'all know about the
errands, right?
When you got to do six stops.
The level of
organizing.
Okay?
Stops.
We got to go here. We got to do that. We
got to do this. We got to do that. And
like even if you write a to-do a to-do
list,
you still went in there and left without
the thing you went in there for.
And now you got to go back in there.
Yeah.
That happened. Course it did.
Of course.
So,
um
but your girl I'm I'm I'm I'm on my way.
I'm on my way.
And
I didn't really have to talk to people
today.
I was in it.
>> [laughter]
>> Marilyn said, "Ain't it
it?" Feel you.
I was in it. I was out of it. I was on
it.
So,
ha
um
Someone said, I think it was Kimberly
says she's worried about me. Let me tell
you something. I didn't know this, but
there's like a WHOLE BUNCH OF PEOPLE
GOING.
AND I'MMA tell you right now,
I'mma be very very small.
Okay?
On this trip, I'mma be very very small.
There's going to be a lot of
personalities.
A lot of personalities.
And I am going to be very very small.
Okay?
When I'm in those types of scenarios,
I get very very very small. I do not
battle for the spotlight.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay. Some people very much be battling
for the spotlight. Look at Reese. Reese
said, "Yeah. Last thing you need is
clashing with activists on a voyage."
Well, it's not just activists, it's
influencers.
You know, it's a lot of big
personalities.
Big.
Large. Grandiose.
And so, when I see
that,
I get very very small.
Now, we had
um
What's Eric's last name? I always miss I
cuz it's a it's a
um
you know, it's a hyphenate.
So, I always forget Eric's last name.
But Eric from um Coalition
of Boys and Men of Color will be
joining.
And
um
Eric Morrison Smith.
And he's been on the show.
Uh you know, I call him finance Eric.
Um So, Eric's going. So, it'll be nice
just meet somebody that's been on the
show. And just to be clear, he's married
and has a baby. I find this is not like,
"Oh, I'm trying to holler at you." So,
just so we're clear,
finance is just acknowledgement of
aesthetics. It's just
Okay? It's just finance Eric.
So,
that'll be cool.
Um Priscilla, who is Communal Press,
um she on on the on the IGs, she'll be
there. She's my roommate.
Um So, it's going to be nice to meet
people that like I communicate on the
Instagrizzles. Um it's also going to be
irritating
>> [laughter]
>> TO MEET PEOPLE THAT I SEE on the
Instagrizzles.
I'm going to be
very very small.
Very
very small.
Yes, Fatima, I'm going with Claudia. I'm
going with uh IFCO. That's the
organization
that um
Claudia is the head of. And um
I know Code Pink is going.
Um
And
who I know like Hasan Piker is going.
Like, you know, names, names, honey,
names. So,
we're going to Cuba. I see people asking
like, "YEAH, BUT ARE YOU GOING TO MAKE
SURE THE CUBAN people get the aid?" I
don't know about nobody else.
I know
that we have aid
that we are physically handing, okay? To
Cuban people.
That's what I know.
So, that is what I'm speaking on.
That is what we're doing.
Okay?
So,
um
And you know, I'm
I understand why people ask these
questions because governments be
governmenting.
That said, that's what we're doing.
Okay? So, that's going down. Now, you
will be able to
um follow. They'll be posting on @ifco
_org
on um
on Instagram.
So, you'll be able to follow on there.
Uh
Yeah, the electricity comes in and out.
I mean, it's I mean
the electricity going is not like a new
thing. It's just that the electricity is
going and there's no fuel.
So, it's it's like if you don't have
fuel, you don't have generators. If you
don't have generators, you can't
generate any electricity to do things
when the electricity runs out. When the
electricity goes out like it naturally
does because of the limitations of the
grid in the first place.
Um Jonathan, you're asking way too many
questions. Um sometimes I need y'all to
think about like does this sound like an
op question?
That's what I need y'all to ask
yourselves. When you want details, I
want you to ask yourself, is this an op
question?
And a lot of times because you're
neurodivergent, I'm not I don't know if
you are or not, Jonathan, but as a
neurodiverge, I have to ask myself, is
this an op question?
Because as a neurodiverge, I'm going to
ask you all the questions.
And sometimes I have to stop and say
this feels oppy.
Like this feels oppy. You know what? Do
do you.
Do you. Live your life.
Live your life.
>> [laughter]
>> Um they are beginning they are getting
the solar panel thing moving up in Cuba.
Um but you know, it's not an overnight
thing.
It's not an overnight thing. Um
And you know, now that we are seeing
there be a new very loud aggressive
attack on Cuba that is being publicized,
it means that then you have to counter
that with a very loud assertive support
for Cuba. That's the solidarity part,
right? And um
that's where we are showing up in. Now,
here's how you can help. You can go to
ifconews.org donate under humanitarian
aid. I am actually going to be doing a
fundraiser when we get back from Cuba um
with these uh let Cuba live shirts that
I designed. So, that's So, if you if you
don't got it right now to give, uh all
good. All good. When I get back from
Cuba and I have, you know, the footage
and you know, just the ability to be
able to share with you all the story in
real time,
um I'm which I'm looking forward to
doing, I will be able to um collect even
more funds to help support the people of
Cuba.
Okay? Um so, there we have
um
ifco_pastorsforpeace.
That's where you can follow the updates,
okay? That's where you can follow the
updates. Um all right. Now, someone is
asking, well, what about solar panels in
Cuba? You know, there are some solar
panels and they are they have actually
increased their solar panel usage in
like record time. However, the reality
is is that there's embargoes. There's
actual sanctions that prevent them from
being able to get access to this type of
thing, right? So, China has been
helping, Mexico has not has been sending
food, but ultimately, they are really
being cordoned out of the world. Like
this is what
the central banks and the IMF do. They
will shut down the borders of a place
not because they can shut down the that
place's borders, but because they shut
down anything coming in. That's why it's
always fascinatingly ridiculous when
Israelis say things like, well, Gaza
isn't oppressed. Gaza isn't occupied.
And it's like, well, yes, Gaza is
occupied.
And and if you are preventing what comes
in, then you are actively sanctioning.
Period. You know, like when I was in
North when I was in South Korea and
they're like, they built tunnels to come
attack us in South Korea. North Korea
built tunnels to attack us. First of
all, that's a lie.
Um then they had like a whole propaganda
video that showed explosions at the
mouths of said tunnels. Mind you,
no explosions have happened.
There there were no That has never
happened.
They literally just did a video about
what they're saying could happen
if
the tunnels are used for what they're
saying the tunnels are used for. North
Korea ain't never said we built these
tunnels to bomb you.
And from what I understand is that when
you see tunnels
connecting from a place that is
sanctioned,
it's so that they can get goods,
services, and people in and out
under the darkness.
Okay?
Under the darkness.
Now, someone said, you know, I'm so glad
that you brought the connection to the
IMF and central banking system. Yes,
because I'm tired of hearing Israel did.
The United States did. Trump did.
Netanyahu did. They serve
a greater God, so to speak. And I say
God because some people think they're
God.
These are not brilliant men.
They're pathetic.
All of these people are pathetic people
who literally feel valuable
by being harmful. They're sadists.
And then there's a whole religion they
can study and practice to do this. I
mean, it's really
it goes back years and years and years
and years and years and years and
centuries.
So, we are here in this in this hell of
a time, honey,
where we have to start calling things
what they are.
So, you're not going to hear me do the
Trump did
Netanyahu did anymore. You're not going
to hear me do the US did, the Israeli
did. I will say it in the context of on
behalf of
on behalf of and I would love to just
call it the Illuminati, but y'all ain't
ready for that.
Okay? Because that word sounds crazy to
you. Mind you, it's just an Italian
word, but it sounds crazy.
Okay? And if you're a hip-hop head from
the '90s, all it SOUNDS LIKE IS
ILLUMINATI.
Y'ALL KNOW I DID THAT FOR ME, RIGHT?
CLUE. CLUE. CLUE. CLUE.
OKAY.
SO,
let's continue to expand. Remember, we
only have two more episodes. This one
and next week.
So,
let me leave you with as many seeds to
germinate in this spring equinox as
possible.
So, let's find out
whom is
among
us.
>> [music]
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Remember,
THIS IS OUR LAST Ramadan episode
happening in the evening. I'm in
Atlanta, tell me where you at. I'm in
Atlanta [music]
here to learn. Drop in and tell me where
you're watching from. WHERE Y'ALL AT ON
THIS Wednesday night?
I'm in Atlanta here to learn. Come on.
Drop in and tell me where you're
WATCHING FROM. WE GOT BROOKLYN, NEW
YORK. PHILADELPHIA, PENNSYLVANIA. Lisa
from Augusta, GEORGIA. PATTERSON, NEW
JERSEY. Running and Aaron in Saddle
Brook, New Jersey. Toronto, Turtle
Island. Nicole checking in from Central
Jerz. We got Brooklyn, New York.
Minneapolis. [screaming]
Honolulu, Hawaii. Aloha. Orlando. Shout
to the 407. Cleveland, Ohio. SAN DIEGO.
BERLIN, GERMANY.
ATL.
[screaming] BOSTON, MASSACHUSETTS. SALT
Lake City, Utah. Fort Worth. KUALA
LUMPUR, MALAYSIA. [screaming]
SHAY FROM NAVAJO NATION.
ORANGEBURG, NEW YORK. From that cold
Detroit.
It's so cold in the D.
WE GOT LOS ANGELES.
ALOHA FROM THE BAY AREA. We got Kansas
City, miserable. At the gym in East
Orange, New Jersey. CLINTON HILL,
BROOKLYN. [screaming]
MEDWAY, MASSACHUSETTS. PHOENIX, ARIZONA.
National City, California. Detroit.
Listen, Reese is with us at 10:31 p.m.
in London town.
Metro ATL. Chicago, Illinois. Detroit
again. Bay Area again. San Diego again.
Melrose and Fairfax in Los Angeles. Say
what up to the Improv. Detroit,
Michigan. Newark, New Jersey. Fort
Worth, Texas. Vallejo, H- HI, SARAH.
SOUTH ORANGE, NEW JERSEY. Essex County,
baby. The Bronx. Durham. Bay Area. Sugar
Land, Texas. Baltimore, Maryland. Cherry
Hill, NEW JERSEY. CHICAGO. PHILLY. Oh my
God.
Y'all are really coming through. Okay.
Denver. University Place. Washington,
D.C. South Boston, Virginia. Maryland.
Kansas City, miserable. Columbus, Ohio.
I think it's repeating some, but it's
all right. Atlanta again.
Oh.
Hot and Nasty Native Territory. Buffalo,
New York.
What [screaming] a loop.
Who's Mar? The island of Ireland.
I'm not going to lie, y'all. I I really
be wanting to just mess up people's days
when I see things like
um St. Patrick's Day. Cuz I was on the
train and everybody was getting on the
train in their green. I really wanted to
stand up AND SAY, DO YOU EVEN KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE CELEBRATING?"
DO YOU EVEN KNOW?
And they be like, "Guinness?"
>> [laughter]
>> So,
there's that.
Um
and Kimberly said she's wrapping from
Winterfell.
So, shout out to the wall, man.
Shout out to the wall. Also, I'm pretty
sure George R.R. Martin like formed that
from the whole like flat Earth theory
that there's a wall um in the Arctic.
And that like that wall basically is
like around the Earth that we live in
and blah blah blah blah blah. And I'm
not even saying that any of that isn't
true cuz at this point
I mean, what isn't true what is true and
what isn't? Um
but it's literally just like I don't
even I don't even have the capacity.
I genuinely I don't I I don't have the
capacity at this point
to believe
that there's a wall and and the Earth is
flat. I just don't have it, guys.
I don't have it.
I know that the moon landing was fake.
That I know.
Them niggers didn't land on the moon,
y'all.
They didn't land on that motherfucking
moon. They didn't.
Cuz cuz if they could have landed on
that moon, you telling me they wouldn't
have colonized it already?
That's how you know.
There should have been
a Cheesecake Factory on the moon by now
if they had actually landed on it. You
know how these AMERICANS ARE.
WHAT?
THERE WOULD have been a mall There would
have been a mall.
Like
if we landed on the moon, we would have
been all like we would have been about
that moon landing.
They can't get nothing going on.
Let's get into our word of the day
before we bring our guest out.
The word of the day is
culpable.
Culpable. C U L P A B L E. Culpable is
adjective, meaning deserving blame,
worthy of condemnation.
Culpable.
I know y'all got some sentences for this
one. I said, "Let me give them a real
juicy one." All right? Culpable.
That's right. C U L P A B L E. Shout out
to all those listening on the podcast.
Make sure you say that sentence in
whatever space you are. Shout out to all
of our replay crew. Culpable.
Culpable.
C U L P A B L E. Who can use it in a
sentence? Let me see y'all.
Um I can use it in a sentence. I
Um can I use it in a sentence?
Someone asked me what I don't like about
Kamala Harris and I said, "Well, she is
culpable for carrying out the
advancement of a genocide. Do I need to
even have a second reason?"
>> [clears throat]
>> Hamper Sand said apathy makes a society
culpable in atrocities.
God damn, you came through swerving with
that one right there.
Whoa, man. All right. Sedge For Rent
said, "People keep blaming Trump for
everything, but as Ms. Amanda reminded
us earlier, there are much bigger
culpable parties." AI and FK47 said, "AI
and Anthropic are culpable in war in war
crimes in Iran and Gaza, at least."
Uh let's see. X Grade Dove's X says,
"People of influence who don't use their
platforms to condemn atrocities are
culpable of promoting the status quo."
You better say that. Uh
Rolando summed it up real quick for
y'all. Choose a sin.
America is culpable.
All right. Uh let's get on down here.
You know what? And this is the one folks
aren't really ready for, but we're going
to say this one Actually, let me we're
going to say this one.
The whole Vatican City is culpable for
all of this.
Yes.
And last but not least because Fatima's
dis dis
Fatima's hatred for Priyanka Chopra is
so
um consistent and passionate that I just
felt the need to make sure that we heard
it and we heard her. Priyanka Chopra is
culpable for being silent in the face of
genocide and rightly getting dragged.
>> [cheering]
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
Like Fatima said, "I hate her." Got it.
Is she the one married to a Jonas?
Right? She's like married to a Jonas to
like a young Jonas or something?
Is she Indian? She's like super Hindu,
right? She's like a Hindu extremist?
Something like that?
I'm trying to tell y'all these actors
and actresses, they ain't shit.
>> [laughter]
>> I'm trying to tell y'all.
I'm trying to tell y'all. I don't been
there, been down. I I don't
I don't been in the mix since I was 8
years old. They ain't shit. All right?
But you know what?
That's why they don't come on our show.
Instead, we have people come on our show
who actually use their brains and use
their platforms to engage, encourage,
and decolonize, and level us up. So,
let's get into our level us up guests.
>> [music]
[music]
[singing]
>> Aidan.
>> [screaming]
>> Amanda.
>> [laughter]
>> Thanks for having me.
Thank you. Okay, Aidan, I got I'm just
going to jump right in because that's
what you did on the internet. You just
jumped right in. What what happened that
made YOU BE LIKE, "I'M GOING TO JOIN THE
TRUTH TELLERS" because I I never saw you
and then I saw you all the time on my
on my um
algorithm and every time you were saying
things that made sense.
It's it's you know, it's been a long
journey. I I think there's been a couple
small moments here and there along the
way, but you know, I am a and you know,
in all seriousness, a white man who
works for himself. If I can't say
something, how can expect other people
to say something? So, it was actually an
easy decision for me to just I've been
doing this on Twitter for a couple years
now, speak what's on my mind, call the
truth out whenever I can. That's that's
what I try to do to the best of my
ability.
Aidan, what is your ethnic background
because you don't look like a regular
white. No.
>> [laughter]
>> Peripheral white OR SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
I'M
>> [laughter]
>> ITALIAN. ITALIAN. SO, so you know, yeah,
exactly. Just on the
>> [laughter]
>> Uh just just crossed the the
Mediterranean Sea then I wouldn't be.
But no, I'm I'm my background's
Sicilian. So, I'M LIKE I WAS LIKE, "NO,
there Yeah, I was like, "What you
[laughter] doing?
Italian." Okay, I see it.
>> Yeah. There you go.
Slavers. Slavers. Yeah, because you
know, it's a different kind of white.
American white is like a very specific
white and I was like, "Well, you're not
that." Um it's the brows, right? It's
the brows. Yes. Yes. I'm not I'm not
WASP, that's for sure the case. Yeah.
So, Aidan, I mean,
one of the things that I love about your
point of view is that it really is
expansive. Um it's geopolitical, but
it's also
um it's not simply just speaking from a
political mind state. It's also speaking
from a philosophical mind state. It's
speaking from a an actual moral and
principled mind state. So, And that's
hard to find these days.
>> [laughter]
>> It's very hard to find.
So, I'd love to hear like how you
um were shaped to be able to speak from
this point of view.
I read Malcolm X's autobiography when I
was 18. I think that was a big starting
point.
>> Say again?
Who put it in your hands?
I did. I did. I was looking for answers
to just whatever and I was also
listening to a lot of hip hop at the
time and you know, Public Enemy others
kept referencing him. I was like, "Okay,
I should check him out." Read that
autobiography and as an 18-year-old, I
was like
>> are you from Canada? Yeah, I am. Yes,
I'm Canadian.
>> out. I heard that out.
>> WE GO. OKAY, YEP, YOU GOT ME.
>> [laughter]
>> THERE'LL DEFINITELY be a couple A's also
in this
There'll be definitely a couple A's, you
know, outs about
>> Outs about. Yeah. So, I'm Canadian. Um
but yeah, I was reading at Malcolm X's
autobiography and it was just way more
fiery than anything I'd encountered
before, you know? It was
really mind-changing and we in the
Canadian education system because, you
know, our southern neighbor, you guys
are a big part of our culture. We
actually do learn the civil rights
movement. We learn it also from a very
whitewashed way, which is that blacks
really want to be with whites and that's
why everyone got integrated and bingo,
all said and done. That's what we
learned. And then as an 18-year-old
reading Malcolm X's autobiography, I was
like, "Hold up, this is all very
different." And then from there, I think
a big part of it was then reading a lot
of black feminist theory. I love for
instance bell hooks is good. Angela
Davis, Assata Shakur's biog-
autobiography is brilliant. And that
kind of just unraveled everything
because you know, white supremacy since
is one of the central axes of power and
once you start to untangle that not from
a superficial level but from a deep
structural moral philosophical level,
everything starts to make sense
including what's going on in Palestine,
including all what they're doing in
Iran, the Epstein files. It doesn't
matter. It all is structured around this
racial capitalism. So,
that's where it started and then I've
just been I don't know posting when I
can and speaking out when I can. So,
yeah.
Who's your circle?
>> [laughter]
>> It's it's um
I don't know, mix of whoever, friends, I
don't know, old friends. I don't know,
like like what do you mean by this? Like
yeah.
>> yeah, because you know, when you think
this way, it can be very isolating,
right? No matter
what gender, class, you know, race,
ethnic background you are. Um but and
and so it requires also
there but but and not but and it
requires having people around you cuz
you constantly are asking questions that
you have to challenge and continue to
challenge.
Right, but I'm I'm also like you know,
you make a really good point and it can
be isolating but I know I've always been
It's really funny cuz I'm very vocal,
I'm very out there. I feel I feel not
how I act cuz people always say, "You're
not like that." But like I always feel a
little more introverted at I prefer time
to myself. So, going on that journey was
actually like just a lot of
self-reflection,
looking just looking into things. Um I
remember when I was a you know, I still
do this a lot in my free time. I just
spend browsing Wikipedia. I don't need
many interlocutors in order for me to
get closer to truth. I think my internal
dialogue helps with that. But there are
people around, you know, friends,
family, whatever may be. But it's
definitely been uh
you know, a journey on my own to some
extent.
>> Say again? Does your family share your
points of view?
Um a little bit.
>> [laughter]
>> I'm more liberal, you know, right?
Whereas I like to go a little more
radical I think, you know. My my my
girlfriend does definitely.
Uh other friends do but it's definitely
again, it was something that had to had
a certain moment. I think Malcolm X was
a big thing. I found school very
stressful, was anxious about life and I
think actually from even a therapeutic
perspective, I think last week you had a
social worker on. I think actually
getting to the root of a lot of things
is also like self-transforming
which is not to say that's not why we do
it necessarily. Our goal is always
towards liberation. But you know, when
you're feeling anxious especially as a
teenager, not knowing not making sense
of things, I feel like a deep
perspective on why things are the way
they are can actually start to be very
reassuring not reassuring in the way
that things are good. It's actually like
oh, everything's awful. Right. But now I
know why it's awful. Now I know why it's
awful. Like that's that's refreshing
actually, you know, right? I do not
believe ignorance is bliss. Ignorance
for me is
really annoying.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, and then and then you see people
lash out in weird ways. They're either
blaming trans people or women or
whatever it may be and that's like
that's obviously not the root of the
problem. So, then it's just like it's
these people, that's why they're they're
you see these reactionary people then
they're also don't have their emotions
together cuz like yeah, you're blaming
drag race but you know,
um Elon Musk and these billionaires,
that's that's perfectly fine, you know.
I'm also an immigration lawyer. Should
have mentioned that at the beginning and
you know, immigrants get blamed for
everything and it's like that's exactly
what the billionaires want you to do.
That's awesome. They're going to make
more money now. Every single time
someone blames an immigrant, a
billionaire gets richer. That's that's
really the truth of it. So, uh but yeah,
needless to say I think I think these
kinds of things
I also
in my journey and just really quickly to
wrap this up, I also knew I was going
the right way because it started to feel
right and things started to make sense
and I do always challenge myself. Then
you start to challenge yourself, you're
like, no no no, actually things are this
really weird way. That is what's going
on. So, yeah. Yes. That's the thing and
I want to get into that in the now of
things because
I feel like people want
there to be a very cookie cutter cut and
dry explanation for the myriad of things
happening all at once right now whether
it's with Iran and Venezuela and Cuba.
And I do think there is something very
simple in the fact that it's an
expansion. Like we're watching
we're watching a colonial expansion
happen in real time.
I think though that
many folks really don't have a handle on
how Iran plays a a really impactful role
in this. You know, I see people saying
like this came out of nowhere.
>> No, it's been 40 years in the making.
More more than that, you know. Exactly.
>> some more context for folks as to
how we got here.
How we got here to cut the the story
short, Iran is the only country or one
of I'd say the only fully sovereign
country in West Asia in the we call the
Middle East. I prefer West Asia that is
resisting the United States. I've done
videos on this too. I say it actually
doesn't matter what you think. Like and
this is kind of funny but in a weird way
to a certain to a certain extent, it
does not actually matter whether people
like the Iranian government or not. The
truth of the matter is there is American
imperialism in West Asia in Iran is the
only country resisting that. It has
allies. Of course, there's resistance
groups in Lebanon. There is Ansar, the
Houthis in Yemen. But Iran is the big
player here that is resisting American
and Zionist imperialism and that is why
they are going for them. That is the big
reason. And I also, you know, I think as
I was listening right before this I came
on, you were saying you know, we can't
focus just on Trump. There's bigger
players always. Remember that sanctions
were imposed by Obama, by Biden.
This is they've been going for Iran for
a very long time. But we're also seeing
why they haven't actually attacked for
this long because the attacks are
actually not going well
for the United States or Israel for that
matter. That's you know, while they bomb
Iran, that's always been in the back
burner for a while and now you see why
they don't bomb Iran cuz Iran's going to
strike back and strike back hard cuz
they have the ability to do so.
Why do you feel like um they So, for
people who are wondering, okay,
they're resisting the US but what are
they resisting?
They're resisting you know, imperialism,
right? Zionist So, so that's a couple
things. Zionism as a settler colony of
the Euro-Atlantic.
Israel is a colony pretty much. That's
the way I see it.
One that continues to expand. They're
expanding into Lebanon, Syria,
everywhere. And American imperialism
being the United States' hegemonic
position which means that the United
States really is the biggest player in
West Asia which means it gets to control
the oil and not only through US bases
but even through the petrodollar which
means 80% of all oil in the world has to
be traded with the US dollar. I I won't
get carried away here but this is this
is THIS IS HOW GRAND IT IS. SO, THIS IS
HOW GRAND IT IS. SO, SO EVEN
SO, SO SO, for your viewers to
understand the
Say again? Are you neurodivergent?
I think I AM.
>> [laughter]
>> YOU ARE absolutely neurodivergent and we
want you to lean all the way in
[laughter]
and info dump on us. Good. Okay, good
cuz I
I might end up taking up the whole
segment. No, it's okay. So,
Yeah, there we go.
So, so the the US dollar is not like
every other single commodity any other
currency. It's a currency that has
financial and hegemonic power which
means people need the US dollar to for
instance buy oil. 80% of all oil is
traded with the US dollar.
And it's through that for instance that
the United States maintains its control
over West Asia. Then the military bases,
the fact that the United States will
strike any country in that region which
for instance
does not obey it. This is the kind of
dominance that it has over the region
that Iran is trying to resist. This is
what Iran is trying to stop and so far
it is doing so. So,
we'll wait for Amanda to come back, I
guess.
>> [laughter]
>> I think one other thing people should
also understand is that this is
something I as I said was going on for
40 years. Iran had the Iranian
Revolution in 1979.
This was overthrowing the Shah who was a
very pro US. And you're back, great. I
was just say I was also just going back
to 1970
Amanda, I was going back to 1979 as well
where the Iranian Revolution happened
and there was the Shah but before the
Shah was Mossadegh, who was a
you know, actually like like all he
wanted Mossadegh in 1950s was just to
nationalize the oil, Yeah. bring oil
money, and give it to the Iranian
people. He was not even
a communist or anything too radical.
It's just like, "Hey, we have all the
oil. Can we get some of the money back?"
Mossadegh was overthrown, the Shah was
put in power. 1979, you have the Iranian
Revolution. You have the Iraq War, a
very devastating war. uh the Iranian
Iraq War, which um I think killed
millions of people. That was their
attempt to get rid of Iran. They weren't
able to do so. There's of course that
I've been sanctions for the last 15
years, and they're trying they keep
trying to get rid of Iran because Iran
is the only one resisting US hegemony,
including the US petrodollar. So, this
is this is a huge thing going on right
now. Yeah.
So, I saw you say the other day that you
do not believe
that this is World War III.
No, I don't. I don't. That doesn't mean
IT'S GOOD, THOUGH.
>> [laughter]
>> WELL, I DISAGREE. SO, I want to hear
your
>> I think there's not going to be World
War III cuz not cuz America or Israel
isn't ridiculous and bloodthirsty, but
because I think China China and Russia
are too smart to get involved in World
War III.
In order to have a World War III, you
would need one of the other great
powers, which really there's only three,
the United States, Russia, and China, in
direct combat, and I don't see that
happening. Everything else, though, like
global recession,
potentially a nuclear strike on Iran by
Israel,
all these things I think could happen. I
don't see direct fighting between Russia
and the United States or China and the
United States happening.
But everything else is going to happen.
It's going to get very bad.
>> I disagree. Tell me, please.
Because I think we have to shift our
our context or even our definition of
what we consider to be a World War.
Yeah.
You know, even just the fact that
how we consider combat has changed,
right? World War I, combat was very
specifically like trench warfare was the
jazz, you know, and prior to that, they
were fighting with bayonets and um you
know, gunpowder pistols and cannons.
Like the prior to that, there's armadas.
So, we have seen the way that war takes
place shift over time. The last World
War, so to speak, World War II, um was
essentially, you know, a lot more
fighting in the air, right? We had a lot
more bombs, etc. I think the concept
also of a World War is colonial in
itself. Because there have been wars
>> like the Vietnam War was a World War in
the sense that it affected the entire
world.
>> Right.
>> Right? And so, I feel like we've
when we talk about the concept of a
World War as being a fight between two
powers,
I don't think at this point that Russia
or China
would bring troops to the front lines
because I think at the end of the day,
they're like, "It's not even worth it."
Exactly. Exactly. And And And Iran
doesn't need that. Iran doesn't need
that either right now. It's Iran For all
your listeners, Iran is winning the war.
Very loud. Trump can say whatever he
wants. He can appoint Scooby-Doo as the
next like leader of Iran. It doesn't
matter what he says. Iran is the one
winning, you know? So, yeah. I think we
also have to acknowledge that World Wars
did not begin with the title, "Oh, this
is a World War." No, no, of course. Of
course.
>> Right? Like it's like it STARTED WITH
LIKE, "WAR ON THE DUKE!" RIGHT? IT
starts with like this one inside It
start Not necessarily one, but it starts
with inciting incidents that over time
draw folks in. And what I what I foresee
happening
is that the way folks are going to get
drawn in
is actually not going to be through
violent force, um
but through economic force.
And
>> Right.
that is violent in itself, right? So,
like Cuba right now
is in a war.
>> [laughter]
>> Mhm.
No, it is. It is.
So, it's it's it's these are the tactics
of war have become
a lot less direct. They actually, you
know what? To be honest, y'all, the
tactics the tactics of war have reached
a level of white corporate woman that we
never saw coming. THEY'RE
PASSIVE-AGGRESSIVE. [laughter]
YEAH.
NO ONE IS ACTUALLY FIGHTING WAR IN AN
old-school way. They're like, "Okay,
we're going to bomb you."
And And but that's also deliberate
because because the United States also
the United States is okay with killing
millions of black and brown people. They
hate, though, when their own soldiers
are killed. You know, right? Like the
life of one the life of one soldier
>> Canadian. You're being Canadian. AM I
BEING CANADIAN? TELL ME, PLEASE.
THE United States does not care about
its soldiers at all.
>> The public Okay, but but the public they
Let me put it this way. I think
No, I think Okay, so so so wait, wait.
The Vietnam War that My point would be
this. The Vietnam War came to an end not
because the Vietnam Vietnamese were
being killed, is because there were a
mounting American soldier
uh death toll. That's what brought the
war to an end.
But it was 10 years later. No, no,
absolutely. No, no, no, absolutely. They
knew
that they couldn't win. Yeah.
>> They knew that the deaths were like
astronomical,
and they were still like, "Yeah, but and
we're going to keep going." Like your
man's um Nixon,
he then comes in office. He could have
stopped.
Right. Right. But I mean, in terms of
the public image, they don't want So,
like for instance, I don't know if
you've seen Have you seen how many
soldiers Wait, wait, wait. No, no, but
wait a second. Wait a second. The They
keep saying like, "Oh, 12 US soldiers
have been killed in this conflict."
They're downplaying those numbers. And
why would But why would they downplay
the numbers? Because Not cuz they don't
care. You're right. They don't care.
They could They would We see that they
don't care, right? But they are trying
to control the image, and I think they
do try to use
indirect forms of warfare very often,
the drone warfare, the uh proxies,
things like that. And I think yes,
you're right. If necessary, they will
throw a million young men into the
Strait of Hormuz as they
Looks like they're going to do.
>> Yeah. But yeah, but I think there is
also
public opposition in the United States I
think does rise when US soldiers are the
ones being killed, which I don't think
is a good thing necessarily cuz I think
it should be
just even black and brown people dying
should be enough.
But I think these indirect forms of
warfare is partly a consequence of that.
And um
But yeah, and we got sidetracked cuz
you're talking about World War III, of
course. NO, IT'S ALL
IT'S ALL A PART OF IT, RIGHT? BECAUSE
>> And even looking at the United States
and Israel, right? Like Yes.
They are, in my understanding of what's
actually at play here, they are merely
pieces on a board being moved by the
SAME HAND. YEAH, OF COURSE. SO, YOU
KNOW, SOME PEOPLE WILL THINK, "OH, the
US is capitulating to Israel. Israel is
doing the bidding of the US." No. The
central banks, the Masons, and the
Vatican, that's who's running the show,
and they've been
running the show. Like, I mean, for an
extreme long long time. And when when
you start to understand the way central
banking and the IMF
have actively colonized the world post
um the idea of colonization, right?
Because
the concept of colonization after World
War II was no longer sexy. So, they
stopped using that term, but it's still
the same the thing.
No, I was going to say also, it is just
settler colonialism in a way. Like this
is the United States 1492, folks. Like,
you know when people say, "When did
everything start going to crap?" And
they're like, "Oh, Ronald Reagan, this"
I'm like, No, Christopher Columbus,
people. That's where everything started
to unravel. You know, if you want to go
even further back, I'd say the
colonization of Ireland, those were the
early steps. And the same thing with the
Reconquista of
Say again? You know who Christopher
Columbus was funded by, right? No, tell
me.
Christopher Columbus was funded by
Jewish merchants.
Or people who were [clears throat]
calling themselves Jewish merchants,
right?
>> Right. He himself was also a crypto-Jew
in the sense that for those who don't
know, crypto-Jew was a term for Jewish
folks who actually
>> Right, because the cuz the the
Reconquista a lot of them had to hide
their identity and stuff like that.
Yeah. But then you come to learn that
like all Jews ain't the SAME TYPES OF
JEWISH PEOPLE, RIGHT? There's some Jews
that are like by faith, there's some
that are Yeah. actually about some
otherness, and you start to understand
that
for what it's worth, we have been
homogenizing Judaism
Mhm. for a very very very
>> Jews, too, right? Like that's really
important. You know, Jews who have
resisted And you know, like this is um
Can I just say something real quick?
>> Yeah, go ahead. Go ahead. Yeah, please.
I just feel the need to call that out,
but let ME JUST SAY, THERE HAVE NOT BEEN
ENOUGH anti-Zionist Jews. Mhm.
The same way there haven't been enough
anti-racist whites.
Yes. This is true. Yes. Yes.
No, I think I think Yeah, I understand
that.
We always do. We should always be more.
We don't want to leave you guys out. We
know that you guys are doing the thing.
You know, we know there are good folks,
but I just want to point out that like
it should be in droves. No, it should
be. And it's always the same like, you
know, the
it's again this
whiteness that is always
people not getting as much involved as
they should. Right? Remember the civil
rights movement, same thing. We had a
lot of whites being highlighted, but
it [laughter] wasn't the white folks who
brought the civil rights movement,
right? But needless to say, what I was
just going to say is is we have um
you know, 1492 is where it all begins in
my opinion. And obviously, as I said,
Ireland, the Reconquista, where they
genocided Muslims and Jews in the
Iberian Peninsula. Yeah. But where I was
going with this is that's where it's all
gone bad. And like
cuz people are people are always asking
like, you know, is the dog wagging the
tail or is the tail wagging the dog?
Like does Israel control the United
States or does the United States control
Israel? It's one system in my opinion.
It is just a settler colonial system.
It's It's just a settler colonial system
that is that is that is rearing its head
and doing what it's done. And I'm sorry,
folks, but also the United States,
Canada as well, Australia, New Zealand.
Yeah.
>> These are just These are just Israel's
on a large scale, right? THESE ARE JUST
MASSIVE ISRAEL'S.
YES, RIGHT? And people might say, "Oh,
BUT THANK YOU."
>> [cheering]
>> AND PEOPLE MIGHT SAY, "OH, but you know,
we're not uh
whatever, you know, we're not we're not
They They might say, "Well, it's not the
same." Well, they do the same things.
>> Well, they do the same thing. BUT EVEN
IF THAT WERE true right now, you did it
before.
>> [laughter]
>> Like that is the thing, right? You did
it before, and that's why there is like,
you know, um all these indigenous groups
in Oklahoma for instance, why are they
out there in the eastern part of the
United States? Well, cuz of the Trail of
Tears. This is all been done before. And
I think though, and I think that's why
whenever you see who is backing Israel
the strongest
it is Canada, America, Australia,
sometimes New Zealand, you know,
basically settler colonies are the the
strongest backing them.
>> Commonwealth.
Say again? The British [clears throat]
Commonwealth. Yeah, exactly. Yeah, well
well, how was Zionism created? There was
Transjordan, which was a British colony,
right? And the Balfour Declaration and
all these other things. And America in
many ways, in my opinion, also just
replaces British colonialism. That's
That's the big thing, you know? So
>> Thank you, Aiden.
>> [laughter]
>> So Yes, that's what I'm trying to
kind of get people to connect the dots
on
because and it brings us back to what
you were saying in the beginning,
because for me, I feel like when we can
connect those dots and really kind of
ground it
it makes the monster not seem so
nebulous and massive, right? Like when I
feel like I started to understand
the actual web and where it's attached
to, like working from the inside out, IT
WAS LIKE,
"OH!" AND IT ALSO REMOVES YOU FROM
having these very perfunctory
conversations. Like I'm not going to
argue about Democrats and Republicans.
I'm just not going to do it.
>> Yeah, yep yep, I hear you.
I'm [laughter] not
>> I'm the same way. And we've we've we've
really reached the zenith with that. Um
where do you feel like you are still
wanting to like dig deeper in your
curiosities around the
around where we are now? Because there's
always something like that is like,
"Okay, I need to understand that more
though. THAT THING RIGHT THERE."
NO, IT'S A GOOD QUESTION. IT'S FUNNY CUZ
I ALSO, by the way, besides all the
other stuff I post online, I just have
my own personal interests like
psychoanalysis, art history, just random
stuff, you know? Definitely that
neurodivergence coming in, I I have to
say. Um where what I'm wanting to learn
more about or like dig in more is
let me think here. I don't know. Like
Like there's always more to learn. I I
do these videos, you've probably seen
this. I In addition to talking about
current events, I do videos on I I try
to also take a very Afrocentric approach
to things.
Everyone needs to learn more African
history because this is the center of
everything. I mean, we were talking
about the World Wars and
in my perspective, World War I is just a
consequence of the Berlin Conference.
The Europeans
in I think it was 1884 in Berlin divided
up all of Africa with the exception of
Liberia and Ethiopia, cut it up for
themselves, drew the lines, and said,
"Okay, Africa is ours. Done."
But what happens after that? If you
conquer everything
who are you going to attack? Each other.
Each other. Yes, exactly. So there you
have it. Um World War You know, the rise
of fascism in Italy, it didn't start in
Europe. I mean, yes, the fascists were
elected in Italy, but the first
consequence the first victims of Italian
fascism were the Eritreans and
Ethiopians. So when you start to take an
Afrocentric
>> again?
Say that again?
>> The first victims of Italian fascism
were Eritreans and Ethiopians
[laughter]
because Italy went to go and
>> of their offerings, etc. Like you have
Trinidad and Tobago which has Pitch
Lake. And Pitch Lake for a long time was
a great source of um oil, but also like
they had another like mineral that they
were
bottomless, you know, resource. And so
like that's just what Because remember,
these are volcanic islands by and large,
right? So like Grenada, we had like we
have crazy rich soil. You can grow
anything in Grenada. It's the exact same
climate as India. Whatever you can grow
in India, you can grow in Grenada. So we
were the number two our island, which is
the size of Yonkers, we were the number
two well, not well, population-wise, the
number two exporters of nutmeg until
NAFTA.
Mhm. The number one
was India. Yes.
>> How? And And And
And Haiti was France's most profitable
colony. You know, why is Haiti all
messed up like that? No, folks, it's
been deliberately messed up. Haiti isn't
poor. It's actually It was for a very
long time extremely rich. It's just the
people are poor. That's the only thing.
And not out of their own doing, out of
their own undoing by the French and
American colonizers. That's why.
Absolutely. So the Caribbean is so
important. Um you know, I for instance,
Grenada, as you probably have mentioned
before, the
uh there was of course um
Maurice Bishop's's uh revolution there.
Mhm. Actually, by the way, a bloodless
revolution. Like Like it was actually a
revolution that, you know, people say,
"Oh, well, no, no, no, no, there was a
struggle." But compared to compared to a
lot of other revolutions you people say
oh why can't we just have a peaceful
revolution?
They they they took power. They they the
unemployment
Yeah, tell me.
>> just tell you.
Please.
Grenada's revolution is a very
difficult topic to actually address
within the context of anywhere else. And
the reason why I say that is because as
far as places where revolutions have
taken place,
somebody tell me if I'm wrong on this.
Grenada is the smallest
land mass where a revolution amongst its
own people has taken place. And so you
have it's literally a village. So like
>> No, it's more
small. you are imprisoning your neighbor
and in other places that may happen, but
that neighbor doesn't necessarily have
people that live 20 minutes away.
Everyone in Grenada is your neighbor.
Yes. Yes. No, it's very tiny. But the
reason I make the point that it was less
less bloody is because I just find this
and just bear with me cuz like
you know, of course Ronald Reagan, the
Satan himself um
uh goes in and of course there they they
the United States invades Grenada. But
it's so funny cuz there's always this
anti-communist propaganda and yet the
social change that had occurred in
Grenada was actually relatively peaceful
compared to other revolutions, which is
fine. We sometimes need violent
revolution. But I just find it even the
one instance where actually goes pretty
smoothly the revolution and they take
power and it's um relatively peaceful.
Even then that was too much. So when
they say revolutions need to be stopped
cuz they're too violent, complete
nonsense. And yeah, and then
>> telling you that one of the reasons why
it was able to be stopped was because
you had Bernard Coard and Maurice
Bishop. And Bernard was a very hardline
communist. And Maurice was like a you
know, he was like communism is cool. You
know, we're going to rock with it. Um
and what I feel like happens so often is
that you know, politicians ultimately
are charismatic. And you end up getting
folks in a room and you end up talking
and it's like okay, you know, you do
this, you do that. Like I saw um
Gaddafi's daughter today you know, say
African say it on, do not listen because
my father even my father who was
completely committed
>> Yes.
was able to be swayed, right? Because
ultimately they really want peace. Let's
be real. So what you're talking about is
facts. Like they really don't want there
to be blood. And so it becomes like all
right, well, I'll rock with you. But the
United States, the Central Bank, IMF,
they're all about blood. That's what
they're all about.
>> [laughter]
>> I know, RIGHT?
IT'S IT'S ONLY NO, it's only cuz of
course you know, in their eyes it's only
it's going to stop cheating on you. He's
not.
It the it's only violence when it's
brown brown and black people doing
anything, you know? Like
Think think think about this. So like
again,
Grenada like you know, this relatively
um peaceful revolution. But hey, like
even like boycotting Israel. Like I'm
I'm just not going to buy this thing.
Like I'm not going to buy oranges. AND
IT'S LIKE WOW, YOU'RE HAMAS. LIKE YOU
KNOW, WHATEVER you like. You know, it's
like it's like it's like I'm just not
going to buy your stuff. I'm not even
like it's not like sabotage. It's just
like hey, let's not Like I thought I
THOUGHT THAT WAS CAPITALISM. I THOUGHT
WE GOT TO CHOOSE what we got to buy and
like you know, uh
>> [laughter]
>> like I thought that was part of the
whole thing, right? But
>> [laughter]
>> like it it it that's that's why I find
it so ridiculous. And going back to what
you were saying about though um you
know, the Caribbean being a extension of
Africa, absolutely
100%
and it's incredible
some of the traditions that were kept
even despite the violence of slavery
both the passage over
and the violence that was done on the
island. Some islands slaves only had a
life expectancy of two years upon
reaching the island. Yep. Yep, look it
up. There were some islands
because slaves were so cheap and these
people were so demonic, they would just
literally work them to death.
>> brown yeah. Yeah, exactly. And you what
was I going to go say about all this?
Like But yeah,
>> in the in the Caribbean was a lot more
brutal by nature of even its location.
Like the sun is hotter. Yes, the sun is
hotter. It's it's boiling.
>> crop to
manage. It's dangerous, you know? I mean
I and and and what I was what I learned
recently too was like
by nature of the isolation of the
islands
the slave owners were even more
devilish because they they they were
basically by themselves. And then they
would take a boat back to England and
act like they're just really nice guy. I
mean if you read any Jane Austen, you
know.
That's part of the reason they killed
all the whites on Haiti cuz like
literally the the every cuz people were
like you know,
>> [laughter]
>> I remember sometimes see this thing like
oh like you know, like uh
what about I know. Just like this this
nonsense, you know, like white genocide
or whatever. It's like yeah, Haiti
that's a good prime example. It's like
No, literally every single time they had
a chance to bring back slavery, the
whites brought it back. Other than the
Poles and they and they and they did not
and on Haiti they did not kill the
Polish people cuz they were like no,
you're cool. You're fine. The French
though were like we're getting rid of
them cuz they they kept bringing it back
every single time So why were the Poles
okay?
Because they were they were indentured
and they weren't slaves. They were
indentured. And unfortunately we've seen
a lot of history where indentured whites
end up siding with the white power
structure. But in this case they're like
nah, like we we don't want to be like we
don't want to we don't agree with this.
And so yeah, there there's and there's
actually still I think
Polish descendants in Haiti today
actually. I think there's like one town.
I could be wrong in this, but I think
there's like one town that has like a
lot of Polish people still in Haiti.
Um I feel like that's the case for many
islands. Like Grenada has like one town
where most of the white people live and
that's where the town I'm from.
Oh, there you go. Voila. Like it was
like a big deal that like my family was
in that town with a and built a big
house and all the white people were mad
at us. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> There you go. And And I was going to say
like the the cultural traditions though
that survived this is incredible. You
know, people think voodoo is a voodoo
unfortunately has been a word associated
with just with anything freaky, but
voodoo was a mix of West African
religion and a bit of Catholicism. And
voodoo ceremonies actually in Haiti,
they used that as cover to actually plan
the revolts, you know?
How the heck do a bunch of people who
are all part of different groups get
brought on on a boat, half of them die,
come to an island
with a life expectancies that are very
short and maintain those African
cultural traditions?
Incredible. And even you know, the I
really hate this always. You know,
people always make fun of the Jamaican
accent and stuff. But part of that's
also has to do with um
the like a lot of Jamaicans were
descendants of the Akan who were aka and
I might be mispronouncing that word out
in West Africa. And so a lot of the
words are actually preserved from all
the way over there. So needless to say,
I mean I'm a Pan-Africanist. Like I
think Africa and African people need to
be united both in the African continent
and across the world. Um I'm a big
proponent of you know, like even some of
the we all know the Black Panther Party,
but heck even like the Black Liberation
Army, a lot of these groups that really
had Pan-African perspective and saw
black people within the United States as
a colonized people.
And so
I think that's a huge extension. I Um
you know, black people might only make
up 10 15% of the US population, but you
don't need a lot of people to create a
huge social change, right? You know,
like that's the whole thing, you know?
We're always focused on majoritarianism,
but no, it's it's the it's people who
are committed and to resisting. Those
are the ones that are going to make the
big change, needless to say.
So where do you see
um the United States if you had to
theorize how the people in power would
utilize the US and Israel
moving forward?
Yeah, this is a really good question. So
I actually think
I think things are in crisis right now.
Um
Do you think they've overextended
themselves? Like do you think that they
really
>> Yes, 100%. 100% they've overextended
themselves.
This is how imperialism works. You have
to go and conquer people who don't who
you say are not like you supposedly.
That's the propaganda.
You use that to do the most forms of
ultra violence. And the propaganda works
by saying the people you're conquering
are inferior.
Now, that leads to a lot of wealth
extraction.
When imperialism comes to an end though
is the imperialists start to believe
their own BS. They think we can't attack
Iran. What are they going to do, right?
We can go and you know, attack Gaza.
What's going to happen there, right? We
can go and attack this indigenous group.
What's going to happen there?
And then they learn. No, these people
know how to resist and fight back. So I
think
there There a miscalculation. I really
do think that. I think
the Iran's a Iran is a threat to the
imperialist, for sure.
But it's hacking it is unraveling
everything. Because, as I said earlier
in the segment, the petrodollar that
keeps the US dollar afloat,
but Iran has agreed that ships can go
through the Strait of Hormuz if they
trade in the Chinese um Oh,
I never I didn't hear about that one.
>> So So, well then there there goes the
petrodollar. Well then what happens
then? Well that means the US dollar's
value as a global currency goes down.
That means inflation goes up, right?
And then you also have to start have
central banks across the world are going
to start dumping US dollars. I know,
right?
And so you're going to have the European
Union banks are going to dump the US
dollar.
>> recession. That's a worldwide recession,
but especially for the United States,
because the dollar is not like every
other currency. It has hegemonic power.
And once you undermine that hegemonic
power,
it quickly unravels. It happened with
the UK pound. The UK pound, the
sterling, used to be the global reserve
currency. And then it no longer was. And
yes, its value went down, right? There
was fears that the US dollar, even in
the '70s, was going to lose its value.
That's why they got rid of the gold
backing of the dollar, because they
wanted to just turn it into paper that
was not backed by anything, but it was
backed by power. But what happens when
that power goes away? You really have a
quick unraveling. And there was even
before this war, by the way, Saudi
Arabia, which I'm not a fan of their
government, but they were even saying
like, "We don't want to continue trading
in the US dollar only. We want to try
start trading in the Chinese currency.
We want to trade in whatever currency we
want." And Iran has now kicked that off.
And I think the US dollar This is a
really big kick to the US dollar. So,
needless to say, the war isn't just the
war. It's the US dollar, it's the
economy, it's oil, yes, but it's also
all these Fertilizer.
It's fertilizer. That. Helium, which is
important for um medical devices. Right.
Yeah, Qatar, I think, is one of the
biggest producers of helium in the
world.
I think they I think they overstretched.
I think they made I don't mean this from
a moral perspective. We hate it morally,
we know that. They they
They're evil, they're bad. But if their
goal is to strategically If their goal
is to advance their interest, this was
so stupid to do. This was a really dumb
thing. Your currency's going to go down.
You're going to have By the way, the
Gulf states, like Kuwait, Bahrain,
Qatar, the United Arab Emirates,
Emirates, they're done. They're done.
They're
Those countries existed
Those countries existed on an illusion
of safety.
They existed on labor that was
borderline slavery, if not slavery. All
the fancy buildings in Dubai were built
by Indian, Pakistani, Filipino
Yeah, uh servants, pretty much.
And now the war's crashed the economy.
All those people are going to go back to
their country. Who's going to build, you
know, I don't know, Burj Khalifa 2 or
whatever the hell they're building,
right?
>> Have you ever been to Dubai? No. Have
you? Yes, but only when I was doing
comedy. I was doing stand-up comedy at
the time.
>> Fair. I hope this is before THE SUDAN
WAR.
YEAH, YEAH, this was
>> Good. Good.
Well, I don't know, actually. This is in
2015.
Um
That might as well be 50 years ago, you
know? It's Everything's changed since I
mean, anything Anything pre-COVID
is like a whole other
dimension. But you know, I I I talk
about it to people all the time, like
how
bizarre of a place Dubai is, because
>> horrible, apparently. Even just from
being there, it's weird. It's just a
weird It's like Vegas. Like Vegas is a
bizarre place to anyone who's never been
to Vegas, because you're like, "Oh, this
is literally just a city for the sake of
money." Like that's it. It doesn't
really have any other value. They'll try
and do little shows, and you know, I
know Usher in Vegas, but ultimately,
that's the whole point of it. And
>> Dubai's the place where people who used
to be really into NFTs would go to, YOU
KNOW?
>> [laughter]
>> YES. IT'S SO
opulent in a way that has no
consciousness, like no cognizance of
time or like the rest of the world.
>> either, you No, well I mean that I mean
there's just zero, literally zero
culture. And sorry, cuz cuz I did say
earlier like I'm interested in art, and
this is what also pisses me off about
the ruling elite now, cuz like
Oh god. So this is This is not even our
biggest concern, folks. This is like
number 100 of our things.
But Minda, what bugs me is
you know, look at like like look at like
um
like, you know, the Medici family of
Florence. Evil, money rich. At least
they created good art. I know. What the
hell? You know what the propaganda that
comes out, the art that comes out? It's
like AI stuff.
It's um I don't know, like just a weird
It's not even good It's not even like
Good. They have not even bestowed us
What Sorry, say again? It's not even
about anything. They haven't even given
us a
distraction.
No, and they haven't even bestowed us
even the crumbs of like some sort of
Renaissance or culture. Like this is
what makes me laugh, you know? It's like
you know, at least at least the the old
scum wouldn't be like, "Well, hey,
here's like you know, here's like Venus
coming out of a shell. Isn't that
lovely? Wonderful. Okay. Oh, here's a
beautiful church." But like You know, I
will say this, Aiden, those people
actually, as devilish, as horrible, as
arrogant, all the things that they were,
they did they were born from culture.
Yeah, exactly.
You know what? Musk has no culture. Elon
Musk has no culture. Zuckerberg has no
culture, right?
>> colonizers, right? So like Elon Musk is
from the Afrikaners. The Afrikaners are
100% colonizers. They do not have a
culture. Like people try and tell me
Charlize Theron is South African, and
I'm like, "No, she is a white woman
whose family were colonizers in South
Africa."
Um and in the United States, white
people who understand and who get it
will tell you every time, "We do not
have culture." Yeah, I know. And that's
the settler mindset, right? Like we're
going to genocide indigenous people and
put up an Applebee's, you know? Like
that's that's really what it is, you
know? So
It really is, though. Like it's like you
I wouldn't laugh I mean, I wish it
wasn't so funny, because it's true. And
so you have now, like you're saying,
you're like, "Wow, like we're not even
getting anything artistic out of this."
>> No, we're not. You have no idea. That's
why I can't I can't stop saying this.
That's why I hate the Crate and Barrel
Pottery Barn aesthetic, because it's all
for the purpose of let's make everything
homogeneous. Let's make everything
cream, white, and beige.
And that way, everybody will be easier
to control, because no like nothing is
standing out. I went to Seoul, Korea
Seoul, South Korea the other day, and
everyone is either wearing dark blue,
dark gray,
or dark black. You might get a cream
coat every so often. But then when you
look at the Joseon era
of Korea, the colors were beyond
vibrant. And that was actually the mark
of royalty, because it created It was
harder to get color, you know, in
fabric. It was a much longer process.
Yeah, purple especially, yeah.
Yeah, so it's fascinating to see how
capitalism has beiged everybody out. I'm
so tired of it. That's part of why I
make it my business
to wear bright colors. You see I'm
wearing cream, but I have on purple
lipstick. Like it's not by accident. No,
I like that. I like that. And And it's
it's the beigification. It's the
inshitification of everything, you know,
right? It's the It's just like
everything has to become more bland and
non-threatening and non-bold. Yes. I You
know, even like um for anyone who works
like in a downtown of any major city,
for instance, it's even the food. Like,
you know, I've I've seen these videos
they call like the bowl of slop, you
know? Where it's just like, you know, I
don't know, rice mixed with guac, mixed
with I don't know, brown water. Like who
knows what the heck [laughter] they put
in there. It's like you you go into your
office, you And we thought cubicles were
bad. At least cubicles gave you privacy.
No, now it's all open concept for
You don't even get privacy, no privacy,
and it's all beige and disgusting. And
I think, though, the reason partly is is
because it's late capitalism. I think
capitalism has actually run out of I
run out of ideas.
And what I mean by this is
you know, to take your listeners on a
little history tour. So up to the 1920s,
capitalism was all about producing. Like
like literally just produce more,
because there's always demand. The
1920s, actually, there was a crisis. And
the crisis was
like this is actually something Marx
predicted, by the way, folks.
There will be so much production, no one
will even Like there's no one no more
buyers. Like how many tables could you
have? How many chairs can you have?
The 1920s is when then you start to have
what we call consumerism. Consumerism
being not just I'm buying this cuz I
need it, but because it's tied to my
identity, because it's tied to my
personal brand. And by by highlighting
this, I'm not saying I'm above it. Like
we're Like look at any clothing,
whatever, you know, art, whatever. It's
all part of
the modern identity. And then so you
started to create planned obsolescence
too. Planned obsolescence being your
fashion changes, your computers change,
everything changes.
>> to turn on an iPhone 6 generation today
and it will not work. It
it it turns on like the battery, the
screen, everything. It will not allow me
to connect to my iCloud.
And what we have Yeah, exactly. But I
now find we're even getting to a point
where the consumerism, the
the identity, the What am I trying to
say here? We're getting to a point where
even this planned obsolescence isn't
working as much as it used to because at
a certain point like you know, I'm I'm
I'm I'm doing this on my computer right
now. My computer is actually 10 years
old by the way and my camera looks fine,
everything looks good.
And the reason I'm saying this is
because there's actually we're even
reaching a limit here. Like how much
faster do you need your phone to be? How
much faster do you need your computer to
be? You have a nice Amanda, you have a
really nice microphone. There is and
I've looked at microphones cuz I'm going
to up my videos and all that, but
there's also a certain upper limit like
after a certain limit you can't actually
like hear the difference, right? You
know, it gets very minuscule at a
certain point. And I think we're now at
a point where capitalism
has run out of innovations and ideas and
now we're just at a point where it's
rent-seeking behavior. It's just
Obviously, your personal rent of your
house is going up, but none of us even
own software anymore. We just we just
pay a monthly fee, right?
And so it's becoming no need for
innovation, no need for making more
stuff, rent-seeking behavior and with
that it's the landlordification
of everything. It's just bland. You
know, it's just like oh, put paint all
over it, you know, that's the little
classic landlord treatment. And that's
why it's starting to look bland. There
is no more innovation, you know.
Previous capitalist, they were scum as
at least to a very small extent you
could say, well, at least they're
creating something new. There's nothing
new anymore. It's getting recycled and I
think it is entering a crisis and I
think that's why it all looks really
disgusting and fake because they've run
out of ideas, you know, oh, AI. AI is
nonsense, folks. I think I really do
think AI is nonsense. I think that the
And so they're trying to find the next
big
>> than people think.
It's it's
It's going to crash and burn faster than
>> Oh, it is. It is. Exactly. Like let's
stay stay the course. Like Facebook just
dropped Facebook just fired like 14,000
people yesterday because BlackRock told
them that it would be good for them to
do so. So they fired 14,000 people and
their stock went up because then they
invested in AI. And the truth of the
matter is that AI is not actually
infallible as much as they would like to
think it is. The concept
>> [laughter]
>> is erroneous. Like it is an actual
computer trained by humans. Humans are
fallible. Like it's it's just what it
is. They also serves it serves
ideological purposes too because
you know, Amanda, there's so much I I I
wrote an article about Unfortunately,
it's paywalled cuz it was a really good
article I wrote like two or three years
ago. I called it AI-deology. I'm just
like it's all ideological warfare
because now you're seeing these layoffs
and they even say, oh, it's cuz things
have gotten more efficient. No, it's
not. No, THE STUDIES ACTUALLY SHOW AI is
making things more inefficient. We know
when we get something that's made by AI,
I look at it like this is crap. And then
if you're a worker, you need to review
it and go over it. It's slowing things
down. AI is complete nonsense.
And what I think it does though, I think
it serves ideological functions. It
helps to justify decisions.
Oh, no person made that, just the AI
did. There's no need to question it. Oh,
you know, we fired these people, the
algorithm just said do this. Okay, done,
right? You know.
Um the I read that article you wrote,
Aiden Subramaniam. Thank you. Um so
there's the there's these things the the
Where was I going with this though?
It also serves another function which is
to um
What was I going to say? Like it it also
serves a function to to occlude things,
to make things things feel more
mysterious when really no, it is just
humans doing this.
But I think there's also something very
serious going on. I think they're also
pushing AI to create confusion. So
we saw Donald Trump even recently he had
a tweet where he said, oh, all these
Iranian strikes on US bases, those are
just AI. They're not AI by the way,
they're not. But AI now becomes an alibi
to say, oh, that stuff in the Epstein
files, those videos aren't real, that's
just AI, right? I think that's what
they're going for. I think that's one of
the big reasons why they are doing that
is to try create confusion
and to make it all mysterious. But
people need to understand
these at the end of the day it's just
code done by people. And by the way,
it's not thinking. It's not thinking for
itself. It's not a a mind, you know,
right?
Oh, the Waymo cars? The ones that drive
by themselves or something or supposedly
by themselves? Drive by them. I know
they do. Of course they don't. Of
course.
It's people in the Philippines
who are literally driving the cars from
the Philippines. And people uh the guy
who brought this to the table was like
so here we are in the United States and
we have to take driving lessons, right?
We have to get a driver's license, we
have to get insurance, we have to upkeep
all of these things and if we fail at
them, we are then of course fined, etc.,
etc. And there is some guy in the
Philippines who is driving this vehicle?
And that's and that's the point of the
AI cuz to to to offshore, to move labor
around and just say pretend it's magic.
People people treat AI like magic. It's
not magic. It's all different labor.
Even for instance
>> really AI, AIDEN. NO, IT'S EXACTLY. IT'S
A MISNOMER.
>> THING. IT'S NOT really AI. Like I saw a
story the other day of these women in
Kenya who are suffering mental like
mental health crises because Yeah. they
are the ones who are sorting through
porn. Yes. I was just going to mention
this. I was going to mention this. When
we when the the content moderation
online, they say it's AI, it's not AI.
It's the biggest center is in Kenya and
they're traumatized because there's porn
there's child porn, there's violent
imagery they have to cycle through.
It is not AI. So the reason why I wrote
the article and again, unfortunately,
it's paywalled, but it was a really good
piece. I called it AI-deology cuz you're
right, it's not even AI. So AI is just
AI-deology. It's just ideology
to cover things up, you know, right? We
cut the workers because of AI. No,
that's a decision you made. Oh, Waymo
and content moderation AI. Nope, it's
that's labor. Oh, you know, we have to
you know, rechange the whole economy for
AI. No, you don't, right? It's it's it's
a it's it's it's it's all just ideology
meant to advance the interest of those
on top. The good thing though it it is
going to come crashing down and I can't
wait for that moment because I'm sick of
it. I'm really sick of it, you know.
The facilities, oh gosh.
I mean, I'm at a point it's it's
interesting when you were
when you were saying about how
it's reached a limit, right? Like the
the the consumerism, but also the ideas,
etc. Because
I experienced that in my own microcosm
when I was in LA. Like in LA
everything is competition and it's at a
point it gets to a point where you're
like, what even what are we even
competing about? Like I already have a
car and it's like, no, you need a newer
one. Like no,
the better one. You're like, but this
one works and I like it. They're like,
yeah, but no, that's the 2016, now it's
2017.
Same with AI.
It's also a
This is literally the culture.
It is. At a certain point I said to
myself
I
I don't even relate to this anymore.
Like this is not bringing anything
interesting out of me. And this is
what's this is what's weird and this is
where like I'm actually going to say
like kind of like occultist or
perspectives come in because we're all
serving like like we think we make
money, but money makes us which is a
weird thing. Like why does So let me
give you an example. Elon Musk is the
richest person in the world. I think
he's also the most miserable person in
the world. And by the way, if if people
want to give me a billion dollars, I'll
be like to the moon, okay? So
like like I I don't get why he's making
this money cuz like just give it to us
cuz we'll be happier with it.
But I always Amanda, I'm always so
confused. I'm like, so why are you even
doing this, you know? Like there's some
billionaires I can see who are genuinely
like, yeah, I'm the best. Like I have
all this money, awesome. I can buy
whatever I want.
But when you look at people like Elon
Musk, I'm like, why are you even doing
this? And this is why it's existential
and I say it's a cult because you know,
the idea behind a cult philosophy would
be that there's like certain
How would I express this? Certain
concepts or entities that we start
worshipping and get so big, it ends up
controlling us, right? And I feel money
is that. Yes. Money and then money
starts and then the weird thing happens
where money starts to have an existence
beyond the people cuz the people aren't
even getting happy from it. Like
and Elon Musk might say, "Oh, well, I
need to make the money cuz otherwise
someone else will make it." And then
it's like So, the money starts to
control us. And that's a very, very
strange thing. Like capital takes on a
separate existence.
Any drug dealer will tell you this.
Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> I'm so serious. Like it it's like and
and you know, they'll pathologize
um a drug dealer in Detroit for thinking
this way. However, this is how the IMF
and the World Bank and the billionaires
and the politicians who are like
scraping and clawing their way This is
how they think. I know. I know. Exactly.
And And it's absurd cuz they're not even
like getting the biggest benefit from
it. I I personally think Donald Trump
would have been happier if he just
became a drag queen. I think that was
his destiny. I think he was put in the
wrong position, you know? He would have
been so happy being a drag queen.
Instead, he became president and is now
wrapped up in all this stuff, you know?
So.
And that brings us full circle to a nice
button because we started with drag
queens and we're ending with drag
queens.
>> [laughter]
>> Brilliant. Brilliant.
So, Aiden, I mean, in your spare time
between learning all of these things and
the law, um where do you see the work
that you're doing on the internet? Like
where would you like to see that go? Oh
my gosh.
>> Or are you cool with what it is already?
No, it's it's really good. I It would be
nice if I'm like, "Oh, like money,
whatever." But like I put I do these
videos. I do almost a daily video. It
takes a lot of time. It would be nice
even just to get like some sort of not
even full monetization, but this is
work, people. Whenever you see us doing
these videos, like look at Amanda is on
right now. I'm on right now. We're
having fun. It's great. This is work,
you know? However, this is work. This is
work, right? So,
I say this, if people like the stuff I
do, I would love if that could just be
something that at least makes a tiny bit
of money cuz otherwise I have to go back
to doing people's like visas, stamping
forms, all that. And that's a really
important work. But if you like what I
do, some money like being able to
monetize would be great. So, that's
where I want to be forward with this.
Other than that, I'm going to always do
what I do. I'm never going to compromise
my principles. I've had
sometimes approaches of, "Hey, do you
want to do this for that?" I'm like,
"No, I'm not doing that. I'm not going
to compromise my beliefs for that."
Because that's existential for me. If
I'm compromising myself, that is no
longer me. That might as well be my
stunt double or something like that. So,
>> And if anything, that right there
has been the full proof OF YOUR
NEURODIVERGENCE.
EXACTLY. YES.
>> [laughter]
>> Sometimes it's just You know, it's funny
and I said I really love psychoanalysis,
like radical psychoanalysis. And often
neurodivergence is just being one both
affected more by capitalism, like having
your antennas more sensitive to things
that other people would ignore,
but also being less accepting of things
and more resistant to it, I think is a
big part.
But yeah, you know, let's just say my
online presence, um you know, I would
love to do more like more videos,
especially uncovering things, showing
things from a more critical perspective.
I love especially looking at more
radical elements of history. One of the
videos that started me, Amanda, was
actually a video I did on how the United
States ruined Somalia and that really
took me off on TikTok and Instagram. And
so, needless to say, these are the kind
of things I'd like to do more of. So, I
mean, how do I do advice? Yeah, please.
Please do so cuz you have a successful,
yeah, thing going on.
I mean, I think that everyone is going
to have to start really thinking beyond
the quick hit. Um
>> Mhm.
And when you have the capability to
retain so much information,
um it really does lend itself to
teaching and to doing so in the unique
ways that we are now able to engage in.
Like I know people who are here right
now. Like if you were like, "I'm going
to do a class called um how Africa Why
Why you need to care about Africa?" And
we're going to cover these specific
countries and it's going to be for 6
weeks and it's going to be this much
money and people would take the class. I
love that.
>> that's what it's worth. Folks really
don't want to be on Instagram. They
don't want to be on YouTube. They really
would love to be able to actually engage
differently, not only with the content
with the content creators, right? And
so, many of us who have been doing this
type of work, we need to shift because
we're actually perpetuating the fuckery
at the
>> Yeah, no, I agree with that. I agree
with that. And And you know, doing
3-minute clips is like fine, but like
sometimes I want to say more and provide
more nuance and go all over the place.
>> And we're still building their platform.
LIKE WE'RE STILL
>> [laughter]
>> EXACTLY. EXACTLY. YEAH. IT'S IT'S SEEMS
like it's a conundrum because you're
like, "But if we don't, then what do we
do?" You know, etc. etc. etc. And like
some people are selling out classes who
aren't even good teachers. So, it's
>> No, that It's horrible. I So, again, as
I said to you at the beginning, I listen
to a lot of videos on art history and
like that cuz again, like I don't even
talk about this stuff online. I'm just
bringing that into what is like
attracting people to knowledge now? Like
that's the thing that I have found is
really intriguing people. Like when
you're able to bring this thing that
people did not even know was a part of
this to this.
>> Yes.
>> Right? Like I see a lot of people now
being very curious about like how
farming has been specifically
um used to harm, right? And like Wait,
what? You know, so it's like those bring
being able to have the critical thinking
capabilities to bring those threads
together, I'm telling you that is not
And because the other part of it, and
this is the last thing I'll say about
it, is that it's an oversaturated space.
And And also, yeah. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> And also, by the way, like so look at
like I'm a
I'm a big shot. I went to law school,
all this stuff. But honestly, education
is
>> know, I do not think anyone who goes to
law school is a big shot. Just
>> Good. Good. You should You should think
that way. Cuz Cuz you really should
think that way.
>> a lot of things. Hence why I say very
sarcastically. But my point is like, you
know, people would say like in this let
me try and break it. This is people have
said this to me. I'm like, "Uh like
whatever." But people say like, "Oh,
like you went to law school, this and
that." But I found for
all my education, education is done so
badly cuz it's not done it critically.
It's um you know, um
you know, the book Pedagogy of the
Oppressed is a really good book because
the banking model The banking model is
here's a bunch of facts and figures,
memorize it. Here's a bunch of stuff,
memorize it. I did I did a recent talk
talking to teachers.
I said to them I said, "Stop this. They
don't need to memorize stuff. They can
They can look it up." It It Some Some
Some like maybe a couple one or two
three principles, memorize that. I said,
"As a lawyer, I'm a good lawyer not
because I memorized a bunch of rules and
laws, it's because I look at things from
a critical perspective, you know?"
>> Yeah, and and I should have said this to
you your listeners, you know, I've had a
bunch of big cases where I've had to
mobilize media to stop deportations.
That is thanks to my critical
perspective cuz I talked with other
lawyers and they said, "Well, the law
can't like, you know, they've run out
Your client's have run out of options.
There's nothing you can do." I'm like,
"Oh, no. If we get people on the
streets, like" Yeah.
>> had to do that. And cuz I know cuz I
know the law is just a system of power.
And so, needless to say, you know,
critical educational content would be
absolutely
beautiful because the way things are
taught is terrible. And of course, no
wonder why neurodivergent people,
probably you have the same experience as
well, like in class I I also had this
experience, especially in high school,
just like napping throughout the class
cuz it was so boring, right?
>> I [laughter]
don't know about what are we talking
about. I would nap, I'd get in TROUBLE
BECAUSE I
WHAT?
I WOULD BE LIKE, that
I can't How do those two Come on. Mhm. I
I got very lucky because I was able to
get teachers like my economics um
and and US government teacher, Miss
Mitchell. Shout out to Miss Mitchell.
She was intrigued by my What? LIKE
[laughter] CUZ
>> GOOD. GOOD. YOU KNOW?
YES. And then at the end of the class,
she was like At the end of the year, she
was like, "So, I wanted to ask you this
all year.
How does it feel to be related to Bobby
Seale?" I'm like, "Miss Mitchell, MY
NAME IS SEALES."
>> [laughter]
>> I WAS LIKE, "I'M NOT BOBBY SEALE."
>> THAT'S HILARIOUS. OH MY GOSH.
AND AND IT only takes one teacher who's
great. Like you know, I had the same
thing. I was uh a C student until I had
a uh a teacher who was like bringing
critical perspectives in. And I was
like, "Oh, I like this." I actually And
that's how I learned So, I'm also a
writer. Like that's how I learned to to
like writing cuz I'm like, "If you let
me write something I'm interested in, oh
my gosh, I will put the citations in.
I'll be like I'll show people who's boss
and stuff like that."
Needless to say, we do need some
critical educational stuff. Heck, even
art. And I don't I actually don't do
anything about art. I want to do more of
that. Like I don't do anything. I don't
tweet about it. I don't do videos.
I've listened to a lot of stuff on art.
And it's good. It's good. It's cool.
Like here's the history of Renaissance.
Here's the history of this.
But what about more critical
perspective? Like How does colonialism
fit into that? Well, we know colonialism
fits into that. Folks, Picasso was
looking at African masks. That's how he
created his style, right? You know?
Right? The um decadence uh for instance,
a lot of the arts of the late 1800s,
well, that was because they were
colonizing and taking a lot of the
wealth and bringing it to Europe. The
introduction of certain paint colors
that were not available in Europe, they
were available in the global south. So,
you know, these kinds of things are
needed. And oh, by the way, and how
Eurocentric art history is, it's just
like 1,000%
It's as if it's as if no art was created
in Africa.
>> yourself to, you know,
do a course that Hm. that juxtaposes the
relationship between the art of Africa
at the same time as the art of Europe,
but that's getting heralded in Europe,
right? And you're like, okay, so this is
when Rem- Rembrandt was doing this at
this time, but this is what was
happening in Mali. And let's look at
that, etc. Because that also allows you
because it also allows you to speak
honestly from a European perspective as
a white European
>> Exactly. Exactly. Exactly.
>> the part that a lot of people also are
afraid to like
expand out of but still be rooted in.
So, I think, you know, Aidan, you have a
lot of options. And like for me, I
realized, okay, I don't want to
um I want to expand minds like in a more
creative way than this, right? So, I
said I need to start doing music again,
and I'm creating a children's show
that's about, you know, critical
thinking and reading, etc. So, like
these are the next steps that we have to
take. We cannot keep I am very much
preaching this, and I'm going to say
this when I'm in Cuba tomorrow to these
influencers. We can't keep just doing
the same thing in the same place that we
are against. It's literally we
counterproductive.
>> [laughter]
>> So, we have to constantly be thinking
how do we lily pad off of this, or else
we are doing the actual work of keeping
it lit, keeping it alive. So, but you
know what, Aidan, you are doing the work
of keeping our curiosity alive. And we
love to see how alive your heart
curiosity is. And
remind me of your
IG address so I can put up on the
screen. Yeah, yes. So, my Instagram is
just Aidan Simardoni. So, it's just
literally first name, last name at So,
at Aidan Simardoni.
>> s i m e r d e r d o n i, right? s i m a
r d o n i Yes.
s i m a i d a n i Simardoni
Simardown
Oh, you need Wait, wait, Aidan with an a
i d a n.
You're close. I'll I'll It's all good.
You know what? I will say this. You're
not the first. People always misspell my
first and last name. But you know what's
beautiful about this? Cuz I have a lot
of clients who are immigrants and hate
having their names misspelled.
I'm always so careful because like
sometimes this happens to me, and I'm
just like I'm It's okay, you did it Like
don't Don't get me wrong, it's all good.
But like as a white guy, I don't want to
be like, oh, how do you spell like
Grual or something like that? I'm like I
listen. I I I go online like my go meet
my clients, I'm like, okay, how do I
pronounce this? Like let me get this
right. And I write it down phonetically.
I mean, I mean, honest, behind the
scenes, I have a piece of paper like you
told me Grenada, and I was like, okay,
Grenada.
Okay, phonetically, it's on there.
Because
my problem is I'm This is probably the
neurodivergence. I'm not an auditory
learner. I'm like a visual learner. So,
I'm like No disrespect to mispronouncing
things. It happens so all the times, and
I'm just like, okay.
Grenada. Okay, Grenada.
>> [laughter]
>> You got it. Yeah, I got it. Yeah. Thank
you so much for joining us and for
sharing with us all of your knowledge.
And we will continue to look forward to
more.
Um so, keep going.
Thank you so much. Thank you for having
me.
>> Thank you for the work you're doing as
well as an immigration lawyer because we
all know
that that is absolutely needed. It's
tough, folks, but someone's got to do
it. And
I hope my job one day becomes irrelevant
as every immigrant gets the ability to
choose where they want to be.
Bam.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> [cheering]
>> WHAT A LOVELY [screaming] TIME,
YOU GUYS.
YOU SEE?
YOU THOUGHT I WAS GOING TO just like
peter off. You thought, oh, once I said
it's the last ones, the last five
episodes, she's not going to really
still be locked in. That's what you
thought, didn't you? That's what you
thought. No.
That's not how we're doing it.
That's not how we're doing it. Now, are
we I mean, I gave you a hour and a half
interview, just so you understand. Y'all
see that, right? It's It's 8:00.
It's 8:00.
So, we are going to actually head over
to the
kickback, the aftershow kickback. But
well, and
um
we're going to be talking about
Well, first I want to tell you this.
Okay, actually, let me change the order
of events. First, I want to tell you
about my latest New Moon musing, um
which is titled uh Happy New Year,
Spring is upon us. You can see You can
read my New Moon musing now on my
Substack, which is called Ethically
Rude. And on my Substa- I mean, in this
article, I'm talking about the spring
equinox. Also, where this celebration
derives from, which many people may not
know, but the oldest celebration of the
spring equinox is in Iran.
The Zoroastrians were the people that
existed before the Persians, and they
were a people that really believed in
connection to the earth. They believed
in the equilibrium of the earth. They
believed that every spring we were
coming back to equilibrium, and that
that would happen not only every spring,
but that would happen eventually the
world over. And, you know, when we are
finding ourselves actively decolonizing,
these are the moments where we can
really dig our heels in, okay? Moments
like this that have been laid so many
centuries before us that are so rich,
they are continued to be celebrated,
that we don't have to try and figure out
ourselves, all right? So, I want you to
check out my New Moon musing, Happy New
Year.
And I want you to ask yourselves where
are you
com- What are you coming into in this
new year? Not a New Year's resolution,
but a New Year's evolution. Where are
you coming into? If you're emerging out
of the cave, you're emerging out of the
soil. We have a new moon emerging today
in alignment with the spring equinox on
the 21st. Where are you emerging? And
the topic is going to be that along with
I want to get into this concept because
I can really relate to this, and I want
to know from our seal squatters how you
all feel.
I feel the less ambitious I am. Yeah,
wow. There was a a quote I I saw on the
internet [music]
which resonated with me deeply. And then
I thought to myself, that's kind of
crazy. Like I I do feel, you know, like
I I want to do [music] things I enjoy,
and I have goals. I need goals. I need
purpose. But am I manically trying to
achieve loads of things nowadays?
Probably not. I do think about this a
lot, you know, and I do actually
struggle [music] with it quite a lot as
I get older and more calm, and I've got
kids now. Like I do worry about ambition
cuz I do think as humans purpose is so
key, right? You want to have purpose.
>> [music]
>> But as I do become more calm and more
like at peace, I do feel [music] like
less and less like I need to achieve
things.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah. I feel that's good.
>> Yeah, and now I know you mean but I feel
it's also like scary, isn't it? It is
scary. I think it's just the purpose
[music] thing. I think it's just if
we're creative and our our outlet is I'm
going to create something. I think if we
didn't have that that's
So,
I relate to this so much. And also
the feeling that is there something
wrong with me not being ambitious
because I
understand ambition
within the context of capitalism.
There's something to be said for
expression, right? There's something to
be said for wanting to cultivate.
However, the context of ambition, I have
always understood within
a connection to capitalism. And I also
understand that as as Rolando's pointing
out, he's fine. That individual
with the hood on is a fine man. Um so,
if his ambition was fineness, it was
achieved.
It was achieved. So,
jolly good
on him. Jolly good.
Um so, you guys, that is tonight's show.
And, you know, I really think that
we are
moving towards a really beautiful ending
to Views from AmandaLand. And I want you
to also know that
you know, I don't look at endings as
like
crash and burns. I look at them as doors
to walk through.
Uh let me just get into this with my
PSA.
P S A [music]
You know, in that clip they were saying
that the more they heal, the less
ambitious they feel. And I would say
that the more I heal, the less failure I
feel. Um you know, I feel like there's
definitely been a practice over time of
feeling like if something doesn't work
out or if something doesn't last for an
extended amount of time that it really
isn't valuable. You know, like I've seen
people who are married for 10 years and
they get divorced and it's like it's a
failed marriage. You lived in a place
with somebody for 10 years. What?
That's success.
>> [laughter]
>> You did it.
Good for you. Um and so I feel like this
this ending of Views from Amandaland is
not actually something to be seen as
like a closing, a shuttering, uh
um a finality. This has been a bridge
and everything that I have done in my
life I have come to understand has been
a bridge.
They're all bridges to wherever the
other side takes me.
And when you start to think of things in
that way, I do think it becomes far less
traumatic and far less um like force
impact on you when shift takes place.
Like even the term rebirth, birth is
traumatic.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay? I saw a clip of white people in
canoes that were going on conveyor belts
from one part of a waterway to another
and that is how I am looking at these
experiences I'm having in my life these
days. Put me in the canoe like the white
people on the conveyor belt and just
lift me over to the next waterway that I
am going to navigate. And I feel like
you can do that yourself mentally. It
does take work. It does take labor. It
does take practice. However, at the at
the other side of that work, that labor,
that practice, I do believe it gets
easier. And as we're talking about labor
and rebirth, people have said
the second one and the third one it gets
easier. The canal says, "Oh, we doing
this again." Pop them out.
Pop them out.
And so the other part of this that I
want to add is that you all
I have been
out here making things
all of my life.
Even before you saw me on TV, I was even
when I was on TV, I was you know, in
someone else's work. But I, Amanda, have
always been making things. I'm making
coloring books. I'm making paintings.
I'm making clips for us to wear at the
gym and gymnastics. I'm making leotards.
If you are a maker, a creator, it never
stops. And the beauty of that is that it
always gives the folks who appreciate
your creations something new to explore,
to exchange, to interact with. And I
feel like that is why so many folks
continue to rock with me is because they
can trust that I will never abandon them
from my creations. Even after I leave
this dimension, even after I leave this
realm, y'all there is so much left over
that y'all ain't even seen.
Okay? THERE IS SO MUCH IN THE ARCHIVES,
HONEY, that you all
the seeds are here to continue to
germinate. So please do not see this as
an end. See this as a bridge. And I'm
going to Cuba
and I'm literally going to be
interacting with people who have been
stuck on a bridge
for decades now.
And they continue
to live, they continue to create, they
continue to reproduce,
they continue to expand, to learn, etc.
Because ultimately there is another side
that we can all see and it's just
becomes how are we going to get there.
And so I am appreciative that I get to
continue that journey of getting there
with y'all even if it's not going to be
through Views from Amandaland.
T S A.
>> [music]
>> HEY!
>> [screaming]
>> COME ON NOW. LET'S GO.
Show your love.
>> [singing]
>> Show your love.
Show your love.
Come on now. They hit me in the cash,
yeah, baby.
Drop a super, baby.
Aiden hung out and I had a good time.
He was teaching us so much. I knew he
was Canadian cuz he said "Oot."
And that was like the show where they
would drop all the slime on those kids'
heads back in the '80s on Nickelodeon.
And you know, my babies, that we are
going to show you show you the love.
Receive and stage up with us.
Show your love. Show your love. Show
your love. Show your love.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> [singing]
[singing]
>> Hey.
Also want to tell y'all that
I recorded my first song and I sent it
to my engineer.
And you know, the first mix back
it wasn't hitting.
I know. I know. The first mix back was
not hitting, y'all.
So then, the second mix back
I couldn't even get through the hook. I
said, "No.
That ain't it neither."
And he said, "You want to hop on a
call?" I said, "Yeah, let's let's get on
a call."
So we got on the phone and
he was I was like, "I can't even get
through the song, Matt." He said, "It
sounds like a calamity."
First of all, that was the most
exquisite word to to define the
thoughts. I said, "Yes, that's what it
sounds like. It sounds like a calamity."
So he was like, "Well, you know, what?
Okay, help me help me get there.
I'm going to get there. I'm going to get
there." And I was so appreciative of his
like diligence. Like he was so dedicated
because I've had engineers in the past
who like if you don't like the first
mix, they just ghost you.
So he was like, "No, no, no. No, no."
And I said, "Listen, if you think that I
my vocals I need to do them different."
He was like, "No, no, no.
No, it's not your vocals. I give me a
shot. Let me let me I'm going to get
this." And I said, "Okay, I want you to
remember,
you mixed my song Man Child. You mixed
my song Trendsetter. You mixed my song
do um let this too shall pass.
Those three songs are three of my best
works
in part because of how you mixed them.
So you are capable, you understand my
voice, and you understand what I'm
trying to do. And what I'm trying to do,
y'all are hilarious. Not not cala
calamanda.
What I'm trying to do is I said, "I am a
jazz singer
who's not singing jazz."
So that's what you have to
figure out.
How do you have a jazz singer exist
in a legit way,
um in a preserved way,
in a music context that's not jazz?
And then he sent me a mix today.
>> [screaming]
>> AND HE GOT IT!
>> HE GOT IT!
He's so got it. And the reason I'll know
when he got when I know when it's right,
when I'm listening to it and I no longer
am scrutinizing. I'm in the vibe. That's
when I know it's right. When I leave out
the car, cuz I only listen to mixes in
the car, and I go into the grocery store
and I'm singing my song like it's not
even my song.
THAT'S
HOW I KNOW. That's how I know.
So, y'all, YOUR GIRL IS BACK.
[screaming]
WE BACK. WE BACK. WE BACK. WE BACK.
So hyped. So,
shout out to Matt Cody from Minneapolis
handling the tunes and bringing me back,
y'all. Bringing me back to the speakers.
Y'all know what to do. Join us over at
Patreon. If you have never subscribed to
Patreon, this could be the night, you
guys. Come on over to the aftershow
kickback at patreon.com/amandaseales.
Only $5 to join. You get all types of
goodness. You get all types of
connectivity. Also, we have a book club
and we just did a author talk with this
month's book of the month. It was
Uh come on.
It was Sky Full of Elephants by Cebo
Campbell and we did a fabulous author
talk with Cebo Campbell. And listen, our
author talks are different. It's not
just
you know, you all watching me talk to
Cebo. No.
The folks got to talk to Cebo directly
and ask the author the questions
directly.
Okay? And I was so glad that we were
able to make that happen and I'm going
to continue to make that happen. So,
shout-outs to everybody in the Seal
Squad. Shout-out to Cebo Campbell for
coming through who promised us that he
is going to come through and preview his
next book with the Seal Squad before it
even comes out. So, you know what I'm
saying? That's the spot and that's the
place to be.
Everybody, wish me safe travels. Keep me
lifted.
Um
you know, and when I say keep me lifted,
I listen, the proper way to keep folks
lifted is not to say don't let this
happen.
The way to keep folks lifted is to say
let this happen.
Okay? So, I want you to keep your lifted
consciousness always moving forward in
abundance.
Let this happen. May this happen. Bring
this happen Bring this happening. Okay?
So, thank y'all to everyone for joining
us for another beautiful views for
Amandaland. And
I will see y'all over there at the
aftershow kickback. And I want to remind
you that I have new shirts available for
all of my folks who are not Democrats
and are not Republicans. Y'all are
changekins. Okay? Folks who are like, um
can we actually like see something
different?
It's got to be a better [singing] way.
And we've got to make [music] it.
It's got to be a better way.
>> [singing and music]
>> And we've got to create it.
>> [singing]
>> It's got to be a better way.
And we've got to find it.
>> [singing]
>> It's [snorts] got to be a better way.
Way.
>> [singing]
>> Redefine
it.
We've been walking this same old road.
How long will we be fools? [singing]
I know where we went wrong.
It was giving grace to goals.
They say the lesser of two evils
is still lesser. [singing]
How they say the lesser of two evils
is still evil.
And that ain't no better. Got to be a
better way.
>> [singing]
>> And we've got to make it.
>> ALL RIGHT, Y'ALL.
IT'S COMING FOR Y'ALL. I'M COMING FOR
Y'ALL. I'MMA SEE Y'ALL OVER THERE at
Patreon. You know what time it is. It is
time for our 30
seconds of stillness. And when I say a
better way, y'all are like, "What do you
mean? Like independent? Like Green
Party?" What I mean is to think beyond
what is here.
Sheesh, manish.
Get that brain percolating beyond the
limitations and perimeters that have
been provided to you.
There are better ways.
30 seconds [singing and music] of
stillness.
Amandaland. [music]
Amandaland.
>> [music]
>> Amandaland.
Amandaland.
>> [music]
>> My bunny and I'm mad.